Mss.530.1.Ar2
American Philosophical Society
- I. Papers
  - Letter to Adalbert Rubinowicz, 1 March 1921; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Stark, Johannes, 1874-1957 (Reel 66, Reel-frame 5)
    Universitetsbiblioteket, Uppsala, Sweden. Letter to Max Iklé, 1905.
    Einstein Collection, Princeton, New Jersey. Correspondence with Albert Einstein, 4 letters, 1907-1909.
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1927; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (4 pages); Starke, Hermann, 1874-1960 (Reel 34, Reel-frame 5)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1932; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (5 pages); Staveren, J. C. van (Reel 10, Reel-frame 12)
  - Letters to Anton Eduard van Arkel, 1947; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (5 pages); Staverman, Albert Jan (Reel 14, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letter to Walther Gerlach, 16 January 1924; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Stern, Otto, 1888-1969 (Reel 19, Reel-frame 8)
  - Letters to Alfred Landé, 1 March 1919 - 24 January 1923; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (3 pages); Stern, Otto, 1888-1969 (Reel 4, Reel-frame 20)
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letters to Niels Bohr, 5 letters, 1946-1947.
    Bibliothek der Eidgenössischen Technischen Hochschule, Zurich, Switzerland. Tape-recording of two interviews in German with Stern, made in 1961 by Markus Fierz and R. Jost; approximately four hours.
    Einstein Collection, Princeton, New Jersey. Letter to Albert Einstein, 1916.
  - Letter to Niels Bohr, 1922; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (3 pages); Stewart, George Walter, 1876-1956 (Reel BSC 7, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1937; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters (5 pages); Stobbe, Hans, 1860-1938 (Reel 10, Reel-frame 12)
  - Letters to Edwin C. Kemble, 1933-1934; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters (15 pages); Stone, Marshall H., (Marshall Harvey), 1903-1989 (Reel 54, Reel-frame 8)
  - Letter to Alfred Landé, 24 October 1924; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Stoner, Edmund Clifton, 1899-1968 (Reel 4, Reel-frame 20)
  - Letters to Arnold Sommerfeld, 9 October 1934 - 12 May 1938; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (4 pages); Stoner, Edmund Clifton, 1899-1968 (Reel 34, Reel-frame 5)
  - Letters to Niels Bohr, 1922; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (2 pages); Størmer, Carl, 1874-1957 (Reel BSC 7, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1936; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Straub, Harald (Reel 34, Reel-frame 5)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1899; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Straubel, Rudolf, 1864-1943 (Reel 34, Reel-frame 5)
  - Letters to Walther Gerlach, 1921; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (2 pages); Strauss, Benno, 1873-1944 (Reel 19, Reel-frame 8)
  - Letters to Edwin C. Kemble, 1932; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (2 pages); Street, J. C. (Reel 54, Reel-frame 8)
  - Letter to Walther Gerlach, 1922; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Stücklen, Hildegard (Reel 19, Reel-frame 8)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1937; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Stueckelberg, E. C. G., (Ernst Carl Gerlach), 1905-1984 (Reel 34, Reel-frame 5)
  - Letter to Samuel Abraham Goudsmit, 1926; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Struik, Dirk Jan, 1894-2000 (Reel 60, Reel-frame 8)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1921; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Struik, Dirk Jan, 1894-2000 (Reel 8, Reel-frame 10)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1938; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Süffert, Fritz, 1891-1945 (Reel 10, Reel-frame 12)
  - Letters to Edwin C. Kemble, 1937; 9.0 Item(s) 9 letters (11 pages); Swann, W. F. G., (William Francis Gray), 1884-1962 (Reel 54, Reel-frame 8)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1946; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (4 pages); Swings, P., (Polydore), 1906-1983 (Reel 14, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letter to Adalbert Rubinowicz, 1939; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Swings, P., (Polydore), 1906-1983 (Reel 17, Reel-frame C)
  - Letters to Erwin Schrödinger, 1952-1957; 11.0 Item(s) 11 letters (24 pages); Synge, J. L., (John Lighton), 1897-1995 (Reel 37, Reel-frame 12)
  - Letters to Erwin Schrödinger, 1951-1956; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters (5 pages); Szilard, Leo (Reel 37, Reel-frame 12)
  - Letter to Edwin C. Kemble, 1937; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (5 pages); Taeusch, Carl F., (Carl Frederick), b. 1889 (Reel 54, Reel-frame 9)
  - Letters to Niels Bohr, 9 June 1920 - 10 May 1922; 15.0 Item(s) 15 letters (27 pages); Takamine, T., (Toshio), b. 1885 (Reel BSC 8, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 6 August 1921 - 25 July 1937; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters (11 pages); Takamine, T., (Toshio), b. 1885 (Reel 10, Reel-frame 14, Reel 8, Reel-frame 10)
  - Letters to Alfred Landé, 24 October 1921 - 3 April 1925; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters (4 pages); Takamine, T., (Toshio), b. 1885 (Reel 4, Reel-frame 21)
  - Letter to Adalbert Rubinowicz, 25 August 1920; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Takamine, T., (Toshio), b. 1885 (Reel 17, Reel-frame C)
  - Letters to Arnold Sommerfeld, 5 March 1923 - 30 September 1923; 4.0 Item(s) 4 letters (6 pages); Takamine, T., (Toshio), b. 1885 (Reel 34, Reel-frame 6)
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letters to Niels Bohr, 11 letters, 1924-1961.
  - Letter to Erwin Schrödinger, 1953; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Takasu, Tsurusaburo, 1890-1972 (Reel 37, Reel-frame 13)
  - Recollections of Fritz Haber’s Colloquium and Erwin Schrödinger’s lectures on wave mechanics in Berlin in 1928, 2.0 p.; Tamamushi, Bun'ichi, 1898-1982 (Reel 66, Reel-frame 13)
  - Letters to Niels Bohr, 1919; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (4 pages); Tank, Franz (Reel BSC 8, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Edwin C. Kemble, 1935; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Tate, John Torrence, 1889-1950 (Reel 54, Reel-frame 9)
  - Letter to Allen Goodrich Shenstone, 1929; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (5 pages); Tate, John Torrence, 1889-1950 (Reel 59, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1931; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Technische Hochschule Danzig. (Reel 30, Reel-frame 4)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1947; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Teller, Edward, 1908-2003 (Reel 14, Reel-frame 4)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1946; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Tempel, Macarius van den (Reel 14, Reel-frame 4)
  - Letters to Pascual Jordan, 1927; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (8 pages); Tetrode, Hugo Martin, 1895-1931 (Reel 18, Reel-frame 8)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1924-1925; 8.0 Item(s) 8 letters (17 pages); B.G. Teubner. (Firm) (Reel 8, Reel-frame 10)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1948; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (3 pages); Thies, Wolfgang (Reel 34, Reel-frame 6)
  - Letters to Niels Bohr, 16 April 1922 - 12 November 1922; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters (3 pages); Thirring, Hans, 1888-1976 (Reel BSC 8, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 8 February 1925; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (3 pages); Thirring, Hans, 1888-1976 (Reel 8, Reel-frame 10)
  - Letters to Erwin Schrödinger, 12 November 1926 - 1954; 10.0 Item(s) 10 letters; Thirring, Hans, 1888-1976 (Reel 37, Reel-frame 13, Reel 41, Reel-frame 11, Reel 43, Reel-frame 4)
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letters to Niels Bohr, 2 letters, 1954.
    Library of the Swedish Academy, Stockholm, Sweden. Letters to C. W. Oseen, 3 letters, 1922-1935.
    Library of Congress, Washington, D.C. Correspondence with Oswald Veblen, 1938-1939.
    Einstein Collection, Princeton, New Jersey. Correspondence with Albert Einstein, 7 letters, 1919-1950.
  - Letters to Alfred Landé, 9 June 1920 - 15 May 1926; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters (5 pages); Thirring, Hans, 1888-1976 (Reel 4, Reel-frame 21)
  - Letters to Samuel Abraham Goudsmit, 25 March 1926 - 29 May 1926; 4.0 Item(s) 4 letters (12 pages); Thomas, L. H., (Llewellyn Hilleth), 1903-1992 (Reel 60, Reel-frame 6-7)
  - Notes on J. E. Littlewood's lectures, "Conformal Representation," Trinity College, 1922-1923; 39.0 p.; Thomas, L. H., (Llewellyn Hilleth), 1903-1992 (Reel 5, Reel-frame 13)
  - Notes on elementary electromagnetism, Circa 1923; 1.0 Item(s); Thomas, L. H., (Llewellyn Hilleth), 1903-1992 (Reel 5, Reel-frame 9)
  - Notes on E. Cunningham's lectures, "Electron Theory," St. John's College, Michaelmas and Lent terms, 1923-1924; 107.0 p.; Thomas, L. H., (Llewellyn Hilleth), 1903-1992 (Reel 5, Reel-frame 10)
  - Notes on Heisenberg's paper, "Abänderung der formalen Regeln der Quantentheorie beim Problem der anomalen Zeemaneffekte," [Amendment of the formal rules of quantum theory to the problem of anomalous Zeeman effect], 1924; 15.0 leaves.; Thomas, L. H., (Llewellyn Hilleth), 1903-1992 (Reel 5, Reel-frame 2)
    See also Zeitschrift für Physik 26 (1924): 291.
  - Notes on S. Pollard's Lectures, Trinity College, 1925; 49.0 p.; Thomas, L. H., (Llewellyn Hilleth), 1903-1992 (Reel 5, Reel-frame 11)
    Includes notes on lectures entitled: "Integral Representations of an Arbitrary Function" and "The Exploitation of Lebesgue Integration in Applied Mathematics."
  - Notes on E. W. Hobson's lectures, "Linear Integral Equations," Arts School, May 1925; 58.0 p.; Thomas, L. H., (Llewellyn Hilleth), 1903-1992 (Reel 5, Reel-frame 12)
  - Notes on R. H. Fowler's lectures on the old quantum theory of band-spectra, Circa 1925; 11.0 leaves.; Thomas, L. H., (Llewellyn Hilleth), 1903-1992 (Reel 5, Reel-frame 3)
  - Notes, "Spinning Electron-Odds and Ends, etc.", 1925-1926; 25.0 p.; Thomas, L. H., (Llewellyn Hilleth), 1903-1992 (Reel 66, Reel-frame 2)
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letters to Niels Bohr, 7 letters, 1925-1951.
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1948-1951; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (5 pages); Thomson, G. P., Sir, (George Paget), 1892-1975 (Reel 14, Reel-frame 4)
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letters to Niels Bohr, 16 letters, 1930-1956.
    Einstein Collection, Princeton, New Jersey. Correspondence with Albert Einstein, 2 letters, 1954
  - Letter to Georg von Hevesy, 2 June 1913; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Thomson, J. J., Sir, (Joseph John), 1856-1940 (Reel 66, Reel-frame 5)
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letter to Niels Bohr, 1930.
    Rutherford Collection, Cavendish Laboratory, Cambridge, England. Letters to Ernest Rutherford, 1895-1922.
    Cavendish Laboratory, Cambridge, England. A moderate amount of disarranged correspondence.
    Edinburgh University Library, Old College, Edinburgh, Scotland. 2 letters of a Joseph T. to Sir A. Geikie, 1877-1878.
    Library of the University of Liverpool, England. Letter to Sir Oliver Lodge (in a collection of the latter's papers), 1886.
    Royal Society Library, London, England. 130 letters, 1884-1934. 35-40 referee reports, 1880-1908, later reports uncatalogued.
    Deutsche Staatsbibliothek, Berlin, Germany. Material at present held at the Westdeutschen Bibliothek, Marburg/Lahn, Germany. 4 letters to Julius Elster and Hans Geitel, 1896-1904; letter to Königsberger, 1909. (Darmstaedter Collection, Fle* 1876).
    Deutsches Museum, Munich, Germany. Letter to Heinrich Hertz, 1890.
    American Institute of Physics, New York, New York. 2 letters to William Duane, 1905.
  - Lecture course on radiation, cathode rays, etc., "Electromagnetic Momentum and Thermodynamics of Radiation," Cavendish Laboratory, 1910-1911; 91.0 p.; Thomson, J. J., Sir, (Joseph John), 1856-1940; Watson, H. E. (Reel 78, Reel-frame 4)
    Notes taken by Watson.
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1944; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (5 pages); Timmerman, W. A. (Reel 14, Reel-frame 4)
  - Letters to Samuel Abraham Goudsmit, 1926-1929; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters (4 pages); Tinbergen, Jan, 1903-1994 (Reel 61, Reel-frame 1, Reel 63, Reel-frame 6, Reel 60, Reel-frame 8)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1935; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (4 pages); Titeica, Serban (Reel 34, Reel-frame 6)
  - Letter to Erwin Schrödinger, 1933; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Tollert, Hans (Reel 37, Reel-frame 13)
  - Letter to Edwin C. Kemble, 29 May 1926; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Tolman, Richard Chace, 1881-1948 (Reel 52, Reel-frame 8)
  - Letter to Linus Pauling, 4 May 1926; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Tolman, Richard Chace, 1881-1948 (Reel 76, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letter to Erwin Schrödinger, 22 January 1938; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Tolman, Richard Chace, 1881-1948 (Reel 37, Reel-frame 13)
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letters to Niels Bohr, 4 letters, 1937-1947.
    Archives of California Institute of Technology, Pasadena, California. Correspondence; manuscript speeches, lecture notes, and chapter of projected book.
    Einstein Collection, Princeton, New Jersey. Correspondence with Albert Einstein, 5 letters, 1931-1941.
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1941; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Tombe, W. J. de (Reel 14, Reel-frame 4)
  - Letters to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1941-1942; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (5 pages); Touschek, Bruno, 1921-1978 (Reel 34, Reel-frame 6)
  - Letter to Niels Bohr, 1922; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Tschulanowsky, W. M. (Reel BSC 8, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letters to Edwin C. Kemble, 1932; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters (4 pages); Tunell, George (Reel 54, Reel-frame 9)
  - Letter to Niels Bohr, 1922; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Tunstall, N. (Reel BSC 8, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Niels Bohr, 1921; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Udden, Anton David (Reel BSC 8, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letter to Werner Heisenberg, n.d.; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (7 pages); Uehling, Edwin A., (Edwin Albrecht), 1901-1985 (Reel 45, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommefeld, 1929; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (4 pages); Uehling, Edwin A., (Edwin Albrecht), 1901-1985 (Reel 34, Reel-frame 7)
  - Letters to Paul Ehrenfest, July 1925 - 25 February 1930; 5.0 Item(s) 5 letters (11 pages); Uhlenbeck, George Eugène, 1900-1988 (Reel 64, Reel-frame 2, Reel 75)
  - Letters to Samuel Abraham Goudsmit, 7 October 1925 - 18 August 1931; 9.0 Item(s) 9 letters (19 pages); Uhlenbeck, George Eugène, 1900-1988 (Reel 65, Reel-frame 4, Reel 61, Reel-frame 1, Reel 60, Reel-frame 9, Reel-frame 5)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1937 - 2 August 1941; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters (6 pages); Uhlenbeck, George Eugène, 1900-1988 (Reel 14, Reel-frame 5, Reel 10, Reel-frame 14)
  - Letter to Harrison M. Randall, 2 June 1930; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Uhlenbeck, George Eugène, 1900-1988 (Reel 64, Reel-frame 4)
  - Memoir, "Recollections of the Advent of Electron Spin", July 1959 - September 1959; 1.0 Item(s); Uhlenbeck, George Eugène, 1900-1988 (Reel 66, Reel-frame 6)
    Duke University Archives, Durham, North Carolina. Letter to Fritz London, 1938.
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1924-1925; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters (5 pages); Undervisningsministeriet. (Reel 8, Reel-frame 12)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1946; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); United States. Immigration and Naturalization Service. (Reel 11, Reel-frame 15)
  - Letters to Erwin Schrödinger, 1946-1947; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters (5 pages); Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität Berlin. (Reel 37, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1934; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Universität Bonn. (Reel 29, Reel-frame 11)
  - Letter to Walther Gerlach, 1922; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (3 pages); Universität Tübingen (Reel 19, Reel-frame 7)
  - Letters to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1922-1934; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (5 pages); Universität Tübingen (Reel 34, Reel-frame 6, Reel 33, Reel-frame 1)
  - Minute Books, December 1900 - December 1937; 3.0 Volume(s) Approximately 450 pages; University of Cambridge. Del Squared V Club. (Reel 38)
    Minutes from the club's 1st meeting to the 192nd meeting.
  - Letter to Edwin C. Kemble, 1928; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); University of Michigan (Reel 52, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1933; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); University of Wisconsin. (Reel 34, Reel-frame 15)
  - Letters to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1936-1940; 5.0 Item(s) 5 letters (14 pages); Unsöld, Albrecht, 1905-1995 (Reel 34, Reel-frame 7)
  - Letters to Edwin C. Kemble, 2 June 1924 - 22 May 1935; 8.0 Item(s) 8 letters (20 pages); Urey, Harold Clayton, 1893-1981 (Reel 52, Reel-frame 8, Reel 54, Reel-frame 9)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 9 November 1924 - 9 June 1938; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (3 pages); Urey, Harold Clayton, 1893-1981 (Reel 8, Reel-frame 12, Reel 10, Reel-frame 14)
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letters to Niels Bohr, 16 letters, 1923-1962. Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 2 letters, 1925.
    Rutherford Collection, Cavendish Laboratory, Cambridge, England. Letters to Ernest Rutherford, 2 letters, 1933-1934.
    Columbia University Oral History Project, New York, New York. Interview with Urey as Nobel Laureate.
  - Letters to Niels Bohr, 1922; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (9 pages); Urk, A. T. H. van (Reel BSC 8, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1949; 6.0 Item(s) 6 letters (12 pages); Uven, Marie Johan van, b. 1878 (Reel 14, Reel-frame 5)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1948; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (5 pages); Van der Merwe, J. H., (Johannes Hendrik) (Reel 13, Reel-frame 1)
  - Letter to Jean Becquerel, 21 May 1934; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Van Vleck, J. H., (John Hasbrouck), 1899-1980 (Reel 10, Reel-frame 14)
  - Letters to Raymond T. Birge, 16 September 1926 - 19 February 1929; 5.0 Item(s) 5 letters (8 pages); Van Vleck, J. H., (John Hasbrouck), 1899-1980 (Reel 49, Reel-frame 2)
  - Letter to Francis Bitter, 1929; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Van Vleck, J. H., (John Hasbrouck), 1899-1980 (Reel 49, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letter to Niels Bohr, 28 July 1922; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (3 pages); Van Vleck, J. H., (John Hasbrouck), 1899-1980 (Reel 8, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letters to Max Born, 13 November 1924 - 8 January 1926; 4.0 Item(s) 4 letters (6 pages); Van Vleck, J. H., (John Hasbrouck), 1899-1980 (Reel 49, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letters to Gregory Breit, 26 January 1927 - 19 February 1929; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (2 pages); Van Vleck, J. H., (John Hasbrouck), 1899-1980 (Reel 49, Reel-frame 3)
  - Letters to Charles Galton Darwin, 4 November 1926 - 28 September 1937; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (3 pages); Van Vleck, J. H., (John Hasbrouck), 1899-1980 (Reel 49, Reel-frame 4)
  - Letters to Wheeler P. Davey, 1927-1928; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (3 pages); Van Vleck, J. H., (John Hasbrouck), 1899-1980 (Reel 49, Reel-frame 4)
  - Letters to Gerhard Heinrich Dieke, 27 September 1925 - 29 October 1925; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (5 pages); Van Vleck, J. H., (John Hasbrouck), 1899-1980 (Reel 49, Reel-frame 4)
  - Letters to P. A. M. Dirac, 26 October 1928 - 22 February 1929; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (3 pages); Van Vleck, J. H., (John Hasbrouck), 1899-1980 (Reel 49, Reel-frame 5)
  - Letters to Paul D. Foote, 24 September 1924 - 8 February 1926; 7.0 Item(s) 7 letters (23 pages); Van Vleck, J. H., (John Hasbrouck), 1899-1980 (Reel 49, Reel-frame 6)
  - Letter to R. H. Fowler, 21 May 1932; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Van Vleck, J. H., (John Hasbrouck), 1899-1980 (Reel 49, Reel-frame 6)
  - Letter to Samuel Abraham Goudsmit, 3 November 1932; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Van Vleck, J. H., (John Hasbrouck), 1899-1980 (Reel 65, Reel-frame 8)
  - Letter to Glenn George Havens, 1929; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Van Vleck, J. H., (John Hasbrouck), 1899-1980 (Reel 49, Reel-frame 7)
  - Letter to Edward Lee Hill, 18 March 1929; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Van Vleck, J. H., (John Hasbrouck), 1899-1980 (Reel 49, Reel-frame 7)
  - Letters to Edwin C. Kemble, 22 August 1922 - 1937; 26.0 Item(s) 26 letters (56 pages); Van Vleck, J. H., (John Hasbrouck), 1899-1980 (Reel 49, Reel-frame 8, Reel 52, Reel-frame 9, Reel 54, Reel-frame 10)
  - Letter to E. H. Kennard, 14 January 1929; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (3 pages); Van Vleck, J. H., (John Hasbrouck), 1899-1980 (Reel 49, Reel-frame 9)
  - Letters to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 25 May 1922 - 1951; 13.0 Item(s) 13 letters (26 pages); Van Vleck, J. H., (John Hasbrouck), 1899-1980 (Reel 8, Reel-frame 12, Reel BSC 8, Reel-frame 3, Reel 10, Reel-frame 14, Reel 49, Reel-frame 9, Reel 14, Reel-frame 6)
  - Letters to Ralph Kronig, 18 September 1926 - 27 August 1928; 11.0 Item(s) 11 letters (32 pages); Van Vleck, J. H., (John Hasbrouck), 1899-1980 (Reel 49, Reel-frame 10, Reel 16, Reel-frame 11)
  - Letters to Alfred Landé, 4 January 1922 - 17 January 1924; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (4 pages); Van Vleck, J. H., (John Hasbrouck), 1899-1980 (Reel 4, Reel-frame 21)
  - Letters to Robert Sanderson Mulliken, 17 January 1927 - 14 February 1929; 6.0 Item(s) 6 letters (20 pages); Van Vleck, J. H., (John Hasbrouck), 1899-1980 (Reel 49, Reel-frame 11)
  - Letter to National Research Council, 1927; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Van Vleck, J. H., (John Hasbrouck), 1899-1980 (Reel 49, Reel-frame 12)
    Regarding J. Robert Oppenheimer.
  - Letter to Linus Pauling, 27 April 1926; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Van Vleck, J. H., (John Hasbrouck), 1899-1980 (Reel 76, Reel-frame 2)
    Includes comments on Pauling's "Quantum Theory of the Dielectric Constant of Hydrogen Chloride and Similar Gases."
  - Letters to Worth Huff Rodebush, 1928-1929; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters (3 pages); Van Vleck, J. H., (John Hasbrouck), 1899-1980 (Reel 49, Reel-frame 12)
  - Letter to Arthur Edward Ruark, 4 January 1927; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Van Vleck, J. H., (John Hasbrouck), 1899-1980 (Reel 49, Reel-frame 13)
  - Letters to John C. Slater, 15 December 1924 - 12 November 1928; 4.0 Item(s) 4 letters (6 pages); Van Vleck, J. H., (John Hasbrouck), 1899-1980 (Reel 49, Reel-frame 13)
  - Letter to G.E. Stechert and Co., 1927; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Van Vleck, J. H., (John Hasbrouck), 1899-1980 (Reel 49, Reel-frame 13)
  - Paragraph by paragraph summary of Bohr's "Über die Anwendung der Quantentheorie auf den Atombau. I. Die Grundpostulate der Quantentheorie," [On the application of quantum theory to atomic structure. I. The basic postulates of quantum theory], July 1923; 4.0 p.; Van Vleck, J. H., (John Hasbrouck), 1899-1980 (Reel 49, Reel-frame 1)
    See also Zeitschrift für Physik 13 (1923): 117.
  - Carbon copies of a bibliography and conclusions of the new quantum mechanics, 1928; 2.0 leaves.; Van Vleck, J. H., (John Hasbrouck), 1899-1980 (Reel 49, Reel-frame 1)
  - "Plans for Study" in connection with application for Guggenheim Fellowship, 1929; 2.0 p.; Van Vleck, J. H., (John Hasbrouck), 1899-1980 (Reel 49, Reel-frame 1)
    Library of Congress, Washington, D.C. Correspondence with Oswald Veblen, 1925-1941.
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1947; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (2 pages); Van Wazer, John R. (Reel 14, Reel-frame 7)
  - Letters to Alfred Landé, 1915-1920; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (2 pages); Varga, G. (Reel 66, Reel-frame 5, Reel 4, Reel-frame 21)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1947; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Veblen, Oswald, 1880-1960 (Reel 14, Reel-frame 6)
  - Tentative inventory of the Veblen papers deposited in the Library of Congress, 1964; 1.0 Item(s) (Reel 58, Reel-frame 5)
    Veblen, Oswald, 1880-1960
  - Letters to Niels Bohr, 16 September 1918 - 19 January 1921; 3.0 Item(s) 3 letters (7 pages); Vegard, Lars, 1880-1963 (Reel BSC 8, Reel-frame 3)
    Bohr Collection, Copenhagen, Denmark. Letters to Niels Bohr, 2 letters, 1941.
    Library of the Swedish Academy, Stockholm, Sweden. Letter to C. W. Oseen, 1918.
  - Letter to Pascual Jordan, 1929; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Vellescu, Ion (Reel 18, Reel-frame 9)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1946; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (1 page); Verdoorn, Frans, 1906-1984 (Reel 14, Reel-frame 6)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1939; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (8 pages); Vereniging voor Facultatieve Lijkverbranding. (Reel 10, Reel-frame 7)
  - Letters to Erwin Schrödinger, Circa 1926-1928; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (5 pages); Verlag Barth. (Reel 41, Reel-frame 6)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1948; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (3 pages); Verschaffelt, Jules Émile, 1870-1955 (Reel 14, Reel-frame 6)
  - Letters to Arnold Sommerfeld, 1935-1936; 2.0 Item(s) 2 letters (4 pages); Verschaffelt, Jules Émile, 1870-1955 (Reel 34, Reel-frame 7)
  - Letter to Hendrik Anthony Kramers, 1924; 1.0 Item(s) 1 letter (3 pages); Vestesen, Hilmar, 1860-1943 (Reel 8, Reel-frame 12)